[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "Ever since Harry Potter was a baby, he was known in the wizarding world as what?",
        "answer": "The Boy Who Lived",
        "wrong": [
            "The Kid Who Survived",
            "The Baby Who Beat The Dark Lord",
            "The Scrawny Teenager"
        ],
        "book": 1,
        "hint": "The name of the first chapter of the book."
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "Mr. and Mrs. Dursely live at Number 4 what?",
        "answer": "Privet Drive",
        "wrong": [
            "Private Drive",
            "Privy Drive",
            "Pirate Drive"
        ],
        "book": 1,
        "hint": "Many readers pronounced it wrong for years before hearing the correct pronunciation."
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Gringotts bank is run by what?",
        "answer": "Goblins",
        "wrong": [
            "Pixies",
            "Ogres",
            "Trolls"
        ],
        "book": 1,
        "hint": "Known in many mythical stories as smart, devious creatures who will do anything for gold."
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "What time did Harry and Draco schedule their wizards duel for?",
        "answer": "Midnight",
        "wrong": [
            "Half Past 10",
            "High Noon",
            "The 12th Of Never"
        ],
        "book": 1,
        "hint": "When the time switches from PM to AM."
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "Who is the Man With Two Faces?",
        "answer": "Professor Quirrel",
        "wrong": [
            "Professor Snape",
            "Professor McGonagall",
            "Fluffy The 3-Headed Dog"
        ],
        "book": 1,
        "hint": "He teaches Defense Against The Dark Arts"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Who nearly killed Harry while trying to save him?",
        "answer": "Dobby",
        "wrong": [
            "Griphook",
            "Peeves",
            "Mr. Weasley's Car"
        ],
        "book": 2,
        "hint": "He is a house elf."
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Where did Harry go on his first trip with Floo Powder?",
        "answer": "Knockturn Alley",
        "wrong": [
            "Diagon Alley",
            "Platform 9 and 3/4",
            "Hogwarts"
        ],
        "book": 2,
        "hint": "A place you wouldn't want to be seen."
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "What came out of Ron's mouth after his curse on Malfoy backfired?",
        "answer": "Slugs",
        "wrong": [
            "Snails",
            "Escargot",
            "Chicken Alfredo"
        ],
        "book": 2,
        "hint": "Like snails, but worse."
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "Why did Hermione have a mirror when she got petrified?",
        "answer": "She knew the Basilisk doesn't kill you if you only see its reflection.",
        "wrong": [
            "She was on her way to a Hogwarts fashion show.",
            "She wanted to see if she was a vampire.",
            "She's the Hogwarts janitor and happened to find it on the floor."
        ],
        "book": 2,
        "hint": "Big yellow eyes."
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "What advice does Lockhart give Harry while they're answering his fan mail?",
        "answer": "Celebrity is as celebrity does.",
        "wrong": [
            "A smile and a memory charm goes a long way.",
            "Instead of doing something halfway and failing, let someone else do it all the way and then take the credit.",
            "Fame and lying go hand in hand."
        ],
        "book": 2,
        "hint": "Something about being famous."
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "How many times did Wendelin the Weird allow herself to be caught by medieval witch hunters?",
        "answer": "47",
        "wrong": [
            "48",
            "43",
            "44"
        ],
        "book": 3,
        "hint": "In the high 40s."
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "What did Professor Trelawney see in Harry's tea leaves?",
        "answer": "The grim",
        "wrong": [
            "The gruel",
            "The grotesque",
            "The hippogriff"
        ],
        "book": 3,
        "hint": "A black dog that means death."
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "What guards the wizard prison, Azkaban?",
        "answer": "Dementors",
        "wrong": [
            "A sphinx",
            "Dragons",
            "Hippogriffs"
        ],
        "book": 3,
        "hint": "Tall black-hooded creatures."
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "What broomstick did Harry get for Christmas?",
        "answer": "Firebolt",
        "wrong": [
            "Thunderbolt",
            "Nimbus 2002",
            "Dragon's Tail"
        ],
        "book": 3,
        "hint": "Something warm"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "What place do the residents of Hogsmeade claim is haunted?",
        "answer": "The Shrieking Shack",
        "wrong": [
            "The Cackling Cafe",
            "The Lifeless Lighthouse",
            "The Mysterious Motel"
        ],
        "book": 3,
        "hint": "The place Professor Lupin used to use to change into a werewolf."
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "Who is the Hogwarts Champion?",
        "answer": "Cedric Diggory",
        "wrong": [
            "Harry Potter",
            "Viktor Krum",
            "Fleur Delacour"
        ],
        "book": 4,
        "hint": "A Hogwarts student."
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "Who sent up the Dark Mark?",
        "answer": "Barty Crouch Jr.",
        "wrong": [
            "Winky the House Elf",
            "Harry Potter",
            "Draco Malfoy"
        ],
        "book": 4,
        "hint": "Most people thought he was dead at one point."
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "What does S.P.E.W. stand for?",
        "answer": "Society for the Promotion of Elfish Welfare",
        "wrong": [
            "Stop the Outrageous Abuse of Our Fellow Magical Creatures and Campaign for a Change in Their Legal Status",
            "Social Pariahs and their Evolutionary Windmills",
            "Stop Putting Elves to Work"
        ],
        "book": 4,
        "hint": "Something about elves"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "What spell did Harry use in the first Triwizard Challenge?",
        "answer": "Accio",
        "wrong": [
            "Crucio",
            "Incendio",
            "Lumos"
        ],
        "book": 4,
        "hint": "Ends with io"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "What stands out about Voldemort's appearance both before and after his rebirth?",
        "answer": "Snake slits for his nose",
        "wrong": [
            "Webbed hands and feet",
            "Green eyes like Harry's",
            "Long blonde hair"
        ],
        "book": 4,
        "hint": "Something above the neck."
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "question": "What is the name of the secret society that fights against Voldemort?",
        "answer": "The Order of the Phoenix",
        "wrong": [
            "The Order of the White Lotus",
            "The Weird Sisters",
            "The Gobstones Club"
        ],
        "book": 5,
        "hint": "An order of something."
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "question": "Hagrid is gone for months because he is visiting?",
        "answer": "Giants",
        "wrong": [
            "Werewolves",
            "Dragons",
            "3-Headed Dogs"
        ],
        "book": 5,
        "hint": "Madam Maxime goes with him."
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "question": "Who is the Hogwarts High Inquisitor?",
        "answer": "Professor Umbridge",
        "wrong": [
            "Professor Snape",
            "Professor McGonagall",
            "Professor Trelawney"
        ],
        "book": 5,
        "hint": "It's a girl."
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "question": "What is Sirius Black's house elf's name?",
        "answer": "Kreacher",
        "wrong": [
            "Krawler",
            "Krampus",
            "Kraken"
        ],
        "book": 5,
        "hint": "Starts with Kr."
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "question": "Who prophesied about Voldemort and Harry Potter?",
        "answer": "Sibyll Trelawney",
        "wrong": [
            "Severus Snape",
            "Sirius Black",
            "Fleur Delacour"
        ],
        "book": 5,
        "hint": "Someone who later became a Hogwarts teacher."
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "question": "Who is Tom Riddle's mother?",
        "answer": "Merope Gaunt",
        "wrong": [
            "Nagini",
            "Bellatrix Lestrange",
            "Hepzibah Smith"
        ],
        "book": 6,
        "hint": "Her father and brother both spoke Parseltongue."
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "question": "Why didn't Tom Riddle like his name?",
        "answer": "There are a lot of Toms",
        "wrong": [
            "It's a short, uninteresting name",
            "It doesn't strike fear in people's hearts",
            "It has only 3 letters in it"
        ],
        "book": 6,
        "hint": "He told Professor Dumbledore when they first met."
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "question": "Who won the Felix Felicis?",
        "answer": "Harry Potter",
        "wrong": [
            "Hermione Granger",
            "Ron Weasley",
            "Helga Hufflepuff"
        ],
        "book": 6,
        "hint": "Starts with H"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "question": "Who sealed the Unbreakable Vow?",
        "answer": "Bellatrix Lestrange",
        "wrong": [
            "Severus Snape",
            "Narcissa Malfoy",
            "Draco Malfoy"
        ],
        "book": 6,
        "hint": "A girl."
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "question": "Who did Sirius leave everything to in his will?",
        "answer": "Harry Potter",
        "wrong": [
            "Albus Dumbledore",
            "Kreacher",
            "The Order of the Phoenix"
        ],
        "book": 6,
        "hint": "A human."
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "question": "Who did Fleur Delacour marry?",
        "answer": "Bill Weasley",
        "wrong": [
            "Viktor Krum",
            "Roger Davies",
            "Cornelius Fudge"
        ],
        "book": 7,
        "hint": "Someone who went to school at Hogwarts."
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "question": "How many Potters left on Harry's last day at the Dursley's?",
        "answer": "7",
        "wrong": [
            "8",
            "9",
            "10"
        ],
        "book": 7,
        "hint": "Less than 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "question": "Who drank the potion so Voldemort could put the locket inside the basin?",
        "answer": "Kreacher",
        "wrong": [
            "Dobby",
            "Winky",
            "Hokey"
        ],
        "book": 7,
        "hint": "A male house elf."
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "question": "Who's Patronus is a silver doe?",
        "answer": "Severus Snape",
        "wrong": [
            "Sirius Black",
            "Albus Dumbledore",
            "Hermione Granger"
        ],
        "book": 7,
        "hint": "Went to school around the same time as James Potter."
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "question": "What is the most powerful wand in the world called?",
        "answer": "The Elder Wand",
        "wrong": [
            "The Master Wand",
            "The Mystery Wand",
            "The Phoenix Wand"
        ],
        "book": 7,
        "hint": "People have been killing each other for a long time over this wand."
    },
]
